

MOHIT KUMAR

Digital Marketer

About Me

Expertise in Digital Marketing. My focus area is search engine optimization (SEO). SMO, ORM, Inbound Marketing, Link building, Guest posting, PPC and Email marketing. Using various Google tools like Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Hubspot, Wordpress, Google Keyword Planner, Google my business and Google trends.



7206589690



mohitsodhya@gmail.com



Yamuna Nagar, Haryana, India

SKILLS

- SEO
- Social Media
- ORM
- Wordpress
- Hubspot
- Semrush
- Ahref
- Canva
- Google Analytics
- Google Search Console
- Google Keyword Planner

EXPERIENCE

SEO Specialist Tru Inc Aug 2024 - Present

- SEO, Client Work, ORM, Inbound Marketing,
- Conducted keyword research to identify target keywords for campaigns.
- SEO for the Client Website.
- Optimize website content, meta tags, headers, and images for targeted keywords.
- Developing and implementing SEO strategies to increase organic traffic, search engine rankings, and website visibility.
- Analyze the website and create an SEO strategy accordingly.
- Monitoring and analyzing website performance metrics, such as traffic, conversion rates, and bounce rates, to identify areas for improvement.
- Develop and execute link-building strategies to acquire high-quality backlinks.
- Stay updated on the latest industry trends and best practices in SEO

Digital Marketing Executive Beyond Codes Aug 2023 - Jan 2024

- SEO, SMO, ORM, Inbound Marketing,
- Conducted keyword research to identify target keywords for campaigns.
- Developing and implementing SEO strategies to increase organic traffic, search engine rankings, and website visibility.
- Monitoring and analyzing website performance metrics, such as traffic, conversion rates, and bounce rates, to identify areas for improvement.
- Develop and execute link-building strategies to acquire high-quality backlinks.
- Stay updated on the latest industry trends and best practices in SEO
- Generating leads through an SEO campaign

CERTIFICATES

Google Digital Garage Certificate

LANGUAGE

- English
- Hindi

Senior Marketing Executive InfoStride Technology Pvt. Ltd. Sept 2021 - July 2023

- SEO, PPC, SMO, ORM, Inbound Marketing.
- Conducted keyword research to identify target keywords for campaigns.
- Developing and implementing SEO strategies to increase organic traffic, search engine rankings, and website visibility.
- Monitoring and analyzing website performance metrics, such as traffic, conversion rates, and bounce rates, to identify areas for improvement.
- Develop and execute link-building strategies to acquire high-quality backlinks.
- Ensuring that campaigns are targeted effectively to reach the right audience, and managing ad spend to maximize ROI.
- Set up, managed, and optimized PPC campaigns on Google Ads.
- Conducted A/B tests on ad copy, landing pages, and bidding strategies to determine the most effective approach.
- Stay updated on the latest industry trends and best practices in SEO & PPC advertising.
- Monitored campaign performance daily and adjusted bids, keywords, and ad copy to improve performance.
- Generating leads through an SEO and PPC campaign

SEO Specialist Modern Streaming Solution Pvt. Ltd. June 2020 - Aug 2021

- SEO, SMO, ORM, Guest Posting
- Conducted keyword research to identify target keywords for campaigns.
- Developing and implementing SEO strategies to increase organic traffic, search engine rankings, and website visibility.
- Optimize website content, meta tags, headers, and images for targeted keywords.
- Ensure website architecture and internal linking structures support SEO goals.
- Develop and execute link-building strategies to acquire high-quality backlinks.
- Stay updated on the latest industry trends and best practices in SEO.

EDUCATION

MBA

National Institute of Technolgy, Kurukshetra 2016 -2018

B.com

Kurukshetra University, Kurukshetra 2012 - 2015